MING-HSU LEE

E-mail: mattlee588@hotmail.com

An experienced regional manager in IT/CE industry. Strong in people management, communication and business development. Highly successful in building relationships with upper-level decision makers, seizing control of critical problem areas, and delivering on customer commitments.

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Abilities to create strategies of sales/marketing and client proposals
- Management ability for putting different groups together as a team to achieve goals
- Management ability for business start-up and product development
- Language ability (English/Japanese/Mandarin/Taiwanese)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2014 - Present GN Netcom (Japan) Ltd.

Country Manager, Consumer Solutions Japan

Jan. 2014 - Present

- Providing leadership and management to Jabra consumer business in Japan.
- Working closely with channel partners for sales driving and growing business in Japan.
- Fully responsible for managing and driving all commercial activities, channel expansion, customer care and P&L optimization.
- Lead the team to identify and drive potential opportunities in e-commerce channels.
- Lead the team to work closely with APAC Marketing team to manage PR agencies and related 3rd party partners for executing marketing activities.
- Work closely with customer services and finance departments to improve the operational excellence.
- Act as point of escalation towards global/regional organization (Supply Chain/ After-Market Services/ Product Management...).

Key Achievements:

- Planned/executed new distribution plan and achieved 43% year-on-year NET revenue growth of Jabra branded Bluetooth devices in 2014.
- Led the team to grow sales and earned the Platinum partner status with Amazon Japan.
- Reshaped the team to complete necessary functions (Sales/Marketing/Business Analysis /Backend support/Detailer) to meet requirements from channel partners and key Online/Offline retailers including Yodobashi Camera, BIC camera and Amazon.

2013 - 2014 SanDisk Limited

Sr. Strategic Account Manager, Commercial Sales and Support May 2013 - Jan. 2014

• Responsible for defining distribution channel partners and driving business of SanDisk SSDs and other storage devices via VAR's/resellers/SI's and to a small extent 2/3 tier OEM.

Key Achievements:

- Identified and signed up the 1st distributor to start up the business.
- Worked with internal stakeholders (Finance, Sales Operation, FAE...) to build a team for supporting commercial business channel in Japan successfully.
- Worked on marketing plan and channel partner program for distributors to drive business in Japan.

2001 - 2013 Logicool Co., Ltd., Tokyo, Japan

Sr. Manager, Strategic Accounts, B2B Regional & OEM Sales Apr. 2012 - Apr. 2013

- Led APJ OEM sales team to generate \$25M+ revenue and drive business growth with strategic accounts including HP, Acer, Asus Fujitsu, NEC, Sony, Toshiba, and other 2nd tier PC manufacturers in Asia.
- Managed client communications and relationships with strategic accounts Fujitsu and NEC.
- Created sales strategies and business plan for APJ sales team to achieve company's goals.

Key Achievements:

- Achieved 102% of sales target in 2012

Country Manager, OEM Sales, Asia Pacific & Japan

Oct. 2008 - Mar. 2012

- Led Japan OEM sales team to generate \$15M+ revenue and drive business growth with accounts including NEC, Fujitsu, Sony, Toshiba, and other small PC manufacturers in Japan.
- Managed client communications and relationships with key customers.

Key Achievements:

- Succeed in managing fewer team members to maintain consistent revenue and keep driving revenue growth after the Great Recession.
- Achieved 108% of sales target in 2011.
- Achieved 112% of sales target in 2010.

Sales Manager, OEM Sales, Japan

Jul. 2001 - Oct. 2008

- Led all sales activities with key accounts including NEC, Fujitsu and Sony.
- Introduced new technology and product roadmap as solutions to customers timely for planning competitive products in the market.
- Represented Sales group on cross-functional team interfacing with R&D, production, and manufacturing to develop suitable products for OEM customers.
- Responsible for supporting customers to resolve issues during product development.

Key Achievements:

- Won the 1st OEM webcam/headsets business with NEC in Japan (2001).
- Won the 1st OEM optical mouse business with NEC in Japan (2002).
- Won the 1st fully-customized wireless desktop (receiver/keyboard/mouse) business with NEC in Japan (2004).
- Won the 1st fully-customized embedded camera module business with Fujitsu in Japan (2007).
- Succeed in selling USB headset/camera/gamepad/microphone to channel partners of console game software in Japan.

2000 – 2001 DELTA ELECTRONICS (JAPAN) INC., Tokyo, Japan

Sales Representative, 4th Sales Section, Sales Department

- Researched market capabilities of projectors, rear projection monitors and CD-R media in Japan.
- Developed new business opportunities in both OEM and Retail.

Key Achievements:

- Succeed in winning the 1st OEM projector business with Toshiba.
- Established working relationship with new channel partner for selling CD-R media in retail market successfully.

1997 – 2000 Kolin-Denon Entertainment Inc., Taipei, Taiwan

A&R of International Repertoire, International Affairs Department

- Sourced for suitable Japanese music products for selling in Taiwan.
- Negotiated with licensors in Japan to make contracts on publishing licensed music CD in Taiwan.
- Created business plans for Sales team and promoters to execute.
- Managed music CD production, advertisement artwork design, and media plan.
- Edited product catalogue for channel partners.

Key Achievements:

- Planned and implemented business plan for all music albums of Noriko SAKAI during 2.5 years and gained a big success in sales in Taiwan and Hong-Kong.

1996 – 1997 Nippon Columbia Co., LTD., Tokyo, Japan

Engineer of Recording & Engineering Department

Maintained recording equipment in recording studios.

• Developed modules of recording software.

EDUCATION

Master, Division of Audio and Visual Communication Studies

Kyushu Institute of Design, Fukuoka, Japan 1993 - 1996

Bachelor of Science, Department of Physics

Soochow University, Taipei, Taiwan 1988 - 1992

CERTIFICATION

.com Master★2001 ("NTT Communications Internet Certificate Examination")

REFERENCES

Will be upon request.